# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, I'm Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In this video I will share a home cooking
# 青椒小炒肉
Stir-fried pork with green pepper
# 首先我们准备二荆条300克
First we prepare 300g "Erjingtiao" chili pepper
# 去掉辣椒蒂之后再切成滚刀片备用
After removing the pepper stem, cut into bite-size pieces for later use
# 不能吃辣的同学可以用大青椒代替
If you don't like spicy food, you can use green bell pepper instead
# 准备小米辣几个切成小片备用
Prepare a few "Xiaomila" and cut into small pieces for later use
# 准备蒜苗2根拍散之后斜刀切成小段备用
Prepare 2 garlic sprouts, and then cut them into small pieces diagonally.
# 准备大蒜和生姜各15克拍散之后剁碎备用
Prepare garlic and ginger, each 15 grams, and crush them for later use.
# 下一步开始准备主料
The next step is to prepare the main ingredients
# 准备五花肉1小块去皮之后切成薄片备用（约150克）
Prepare 1 small piece of pork belly (skin removed) and cut into thin slices (about 150 g)
# 同学们五花肉必须切得越薄越好
You must cut the pork belly as thin as possible
# 这样更容易炒香爆出猪油
This makes it easier to render the fat
# 准备里脊肉1小块逆着纹路切成薄片备用（约100克）
Prepare a small piece of tenderloin and slice it against the grain for later use (about 100g)
# 同学们加里脊肉的目的是让成菜肥瘦均匀
The purpose of adding tenderloin is so that the dish has both fatty and lean meat
# 使其适合更广泛的人群食用
Make it suitable for a wider population
# 下一步开始准备腌里脊肉
The next step is to marinate the tenderloin
# 碗中加入少许食用盐
Add a pinch of salt to the bowl
# 加入少许胡椒粉
Add a little pepper
# 加入生抽酱油2克
Add 2 grams of light soy sauce
# 加入蛋清2克之后抓拌均匀
Add 2 grams of egg white and stir well
# 中途加入少许的干淀粉拌匀
Add a little starch halfway through and mix well
# 加干淀粉可以保持里脊肉嫩而不柴
Adding starch can keep the tenderloin tender and juicy
# 最后加入适量的植物油拌匀即可
Finally add an appropriate amount of vegetable oil and mix well
# 目的是防止下锅起团
The purpose is to prevent clumping
# 下一步开始制作
Next step is frying
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First let's heat the wok
# 锅烧热之后将切好的辣椒下锅干炒2分钟
After the wok is hot, fry the chili peppers for 2 minutes
# 这一步的目的是提前将辣椒炒香
The purpose of this step is to bring out peppers' aroma
# 同学们切记这一步必须保持中火防止炒糊
please remember that at this step, use medium heat to prevent burning
# 将辣椒炒出虎皮状即可倒出备用
Fry until the skin gets crispy and wrinkly then put it aside
# 辣椒倒出之后将锅洗干净下一步开始炒肉
After the peppers are poured out, clean the wok and start frying the meat.
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First we preheat the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的油滑锅
After the wok is hot, add moderate amount of oil to grease the wok
# 滑好锅之后将热油倒出
Pour out the hot oil afterwards
# 然后将切好的五花肉下锅爆炒1分钟
Then stir-fry the cut pork belly for 1 minute
# 这一步的目的是将五花肉爆香炒出猪油
The purpose of this step is to render out the fat
# 同学们家庭小灶则需要2分钟左右
It takes about 2 minutes if using family stove
# 1分钟之后将腌好的里脊肉下锅翻炒几下炒至8成熟
After 1 minute, stir-fry the marinated pork tenderloin a few times until it is medium well.
# 中途加入剁好的姜蒜末爆香
Add chopped ginger and garlic in between
# 里脊肉炒至8成熟之后下一步开始调味
The next step is to seasoning
# 锅中加入蚝油6克
Add 6 grams of oyster sauce to the wok
# 加入生抽酱油4克从锅边淋入
Add 4 grams of soy sauce
# 加入少许白糖提鲜
Add a little sugar to enhance the flavor
# 加入少许胡椒粉
Add a little pepper
# 最后加入老抽2克调色
Finally add 2g dark soy sauce for color
# 翻炒均匀之后将处理好的辣椒下锅翻炒均匀
Add fried peppers and stir fry to fully combine everything.
# 最后再加入切好的蒜苗炒至断生即可出锅装盘
Finally, add the chopped garlic sprouts and stir-fry until they are softened.
# 一道非常美味的家常菜小炒肉就制作完成
A very delicious homemade dish Stir Fried Pork is done
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，采用五花肉和里脊肉搭配可以显得肥瘦皆宜
# 第二，提前炒香的辣椒味更具农家风味
# 第三，此菜可以不用放盐，只需要蚝油酱油调咸味即可
# 小炒肉的技术总结完毕
Technical summary below
First, use both pork belly and tenderloin for texture contrast
Second, fry the chili first so it tastes more country style
Third, this dish does not need salt. Only oyster sauce and soy sauce for salty taste
The technical summary of the Stir Fried Pork is completed